So very quickly, yesterday we looked at the request and response cycle for an API.
Think of routing in Flask as the same thing. Flask is our web application.
Consider our server. So our client is the browser. In this case, I'm asking for the root URL for my server.
And my server is returning a response, just a plain old string that says hello world.
Declaring routes in Flask, we saw the, that forward slash resolves to the root.
But we can also put in as many paths as we want. Let's say,
funjora worlds returns, funjora worlds. By default, we want all of our visitors to see hello worlds.
But optionally, if they want to take the special path for, let's say, France.
We can do that. So we would want to declare a new app route. So still the forward slash, that's the root.
But now I'm going to say forward slash French.
And make sure that your, your Flask app is running here.
Before we do that, I'm going to show you something pretty handy.
In Flask, you can have a debug mode for your local environment where you can have your site, just live reload your code.
So that you don't have to type your new function, change your route, play around with things.
Kill the server, start it back up again, pretty tedious process. So here, just like we set the Flask app to be hello.py.
We want to back up a little bit. And we want to set a new environment variable.
And we're going to set Flask underscore n to equal development.
So I'm just going to copy that.
So for Mac, it would be this. And for Windows.
Hopefully, sorry about that.
For Windows, hopefully, I can just come on me as code.
You are not collaborating with me today.
Hopefully, I can just copy and paste this whole thing and that does the right trick.
So I'm saying that Flask n is equal to development.
For Windows.
Okay, now when we run Flask with our development environment, we'll see that debug mode is on.
And it'll say, restarting with stat, the debugger is active.
And now, let's see, if we go to our web page, we should be able to load it just fine.
Now, if we try to add the path French, we'll see that the more specific route was picked up.
Or I'm sorry, the route for French was picked up.
You can do a lot with this opt. route. You can even accept parameters.
You can give type hints for those parameters.
You can specify which HTTP methods you want to accept in your route, for example, just get or just post.
Let's try to make a new route that accepts a parameter.
So I'm going to call this app route.
For slash name, forward slash, and then a new symbol here, these brackets.
And I'm going to put a name in here.
Now I can say, I'm going to take a new function here.
And my function has to accept this one parameter, because I defined it in the app route.
And I'm going to return an F string.
It's going to say hello and name.
Okay, now, saving this, I don't have to stop and start my server.
I'm going to go to the path name slash nina.
And now, whatever I put at the end of this URL, we'll be used as a parameter.